Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals M-Z, Series II
  - Woodger, Harriet Mabel
    - Typescript memoir "Pigtails: Autobiographical Sketches on Travels to China and Kenya and the life found there, 1932-1966", circa 1986 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Wooding, Ada E.
    Ada E. Wooding was a missionary in San Salvador, Congo, serving under the Baptist Missionary Society.
    - Quarterly letter from Wooding addressed to "My dear Friends" describes mission work and native practices., 1904 (Box 282, Folder 7)
  - Woods, Leonard
    1774 Jun 19 -Born in Princeton, MA; 1796 -Graduated from Harvard; 1798 -Ordained minister at Newbury, MA; 1808-1846 -Professor of theology, Andover Seminary; 1854 -Died.
    - Bound volume of notes on lectures given by Woods, 1837-1838. Volume also includes minimal notes on lectures by Professors Dwight, Emerson, and Stuart (Box 292)
  - Wuerffel, Mark and Sonja
    Missionaries serving in Papua New Guinea under Wycliffe Bible Translators.
    - Newsletters, 1992-2010 (Box 335, Folder 17)
  - Yardley, Henry Albert
    Yardley (1834-1882) taught at Berkeley Divinity School, Middletown, Connecticut from 1863 to 1882.
    - Bound volume of holograph notes taken by Henry T. Scudder on lectures of Prof. Henry A. Yardley (n.d.). Lectures on: Natural Theology, Christian Evidences (Box 279)
  - Zanisi, Angelo Saverio
    Zanisi worked as a missionary in North Malabar, India from 1951-1956. He moved to the Philippines in 1956, working at the Papal Embassy in Manilla for a year and then beginning a new Mission on the island of Samar in the town of Jipapad. He left the Philippines in 1983.
    - 7 large photographs of missionaries and native Philippine people., late 1960s - early 1970s (Box 458, Folder 1)
    - 14 photographs in color of native Philippine people without missionaries in the photographs., late 1970s - early 1980s (Box 458, Folder 2)
    - 20 photographs in color of native Philippine people with missionaries., late 1970s - early 1980s (Box 458, Folder 3)
    - 13 photographs in color of scenes from the Philippines without any people in them., late 1970s - early 1980s (Box 458, Folder 4)
    - 153 small black-and-white photographs of native Philippine people., 1950s (Box 458, Folder 5)
    - 155 small black-and-white photographs of missionaries with native Philippine people., 1950s (Box 458, Folder 6)
    - 81 small black-and-white photographs of scenes from the Philippines without any people in them., 1950s (Box 458, Folder 7)
    - 106 black-and-white photographs of native Philippine people without missionaries in the photographs., 1960s-1970s (Box 458, Folder 8)
    - 134 black-and-white photographs of native Philippine people and missionaries in the Philippines., 1960s-1970s (Box 458, Folder 9)
    - 21 black-and-white photographs of missionaries in the Philippines., 1960s-1970s (Box 458, Folder 10)
    - 23 black-and-white photographs of scenes from the Philippines without any people in them., 1960s-1970s (Box 458, Folder 11)
    - 149 black-and-white photographs of scenes with natives and missionaries in the Philippines., 1951-1952 (Box 458, Folder 12)
    - 222 black-and-white and color photographs of missionaries and natives in the Philippines., 1960s (Box 458, Folder 13)
    - 121 color photographs of missionaries and natives in the Philippines with a corresponding letter written in Italian., 1980s (Box 458, Folder 14)
    - Two small Kodak Album Prints albums with black-and-white photographs in them., no date (Box 458, Folder 15)
    - 16 small, flexible albums with photographs in them., 1950s-1970s (Box 458, Folder 16)
    - Three small photograph albums with 16, 17, and 17 photographs in them, respectively. Most of the photographs are colored, but a few are black-and-white., 1970s-1980s (Box 458, Folder 17)
    - Green album with an Egyptian scene on the front of it. It has 68 black-and-white photographs in it., 1956-1962 (Box 458, Folder 18)
    - Blue album with an Egyptian scene on the front of it. It has 44 black-and-white photographs in it., 1951-1962 (Box 458, Folder 19)
    - Red photograph album with 43 black-and-white photographs in it., 1951-1962 (Box 458, Folder 20)
    - Brown album with an image of a boy and a girl on the front of it. The album contains 189 black-and-white photographs of missionary work in the Philippines., ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 458, Folder 21)
    - Photograph album with 78 color photographs in it., 1980s (Box 458, Folder 22)
    - Two awards given to Fr. Angelo Saverio Zanisi for his work as a missionary., no date (Box 458, Folder 23)
    - Hipapad Catholic Mission bulletin. Written in Italian., 1972 (Box 458, Folder 24)
    - Small box with a leather pouch inside containing a rosary. Citation, no date (Box 458, Folder 25)
    - Additional photographs (Box 459, Folder 1-9)
    - Additional photographs (Box 460, Folder 1-10)
    - Additional photographs (Box 461, Folder 1-4)
  - Zorn, Herbert M.
    Zorn served with the Theological Education Fund (TEF) based in London from 1972 to 1975. He was coordinator of a study on the viability of theological education in the majority world, which was published as "Viability in Context"
    - "Viability in context: a study of the financial viability of theological education in the Third World, seedbed or sheltered garden?", 1975 (Box 451, Folder 7)
    - Travel notes of Zorn during evaluation of theological education institutions in India, Indonesia, Philippines, Hong Kong, Taiwan, Korea, Africa, etc.: typescript and CD, 1972-1975 (Box 451, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified
    - 250 page manuscript diary written by unidentified woman missionary, mostly in Kenya, where she was working for the African Inland Mission. Colleagues Charles and Florence Skoda are mentioned. She tells in detail of her daily work and teaching., 1938-1942 (Box 423, Folder 7)
    - Approximately forty handwritten sermons, some dated but with no indication of author or locations preached; one printed funeral sermon, one pamphlet titled "Mount-Carmel, Feb. 1822", circa 1784-1827 (Box 45, Folder 1-3)